# 您又做大白菜？我來個珊瑚白菜。
Are you cooking napa cabbage again? I am going to make Coral Napa Cabbage.
# 這葉兒讓我使了，白菜幫他不能糟盡啊
I have already used the leaves, but we won't waste the stems either.
# 冬天的白菜最好，它脆
Napa cabbage tastes the best in winter. It's crunchy.
# 我們呢，把這白菜切成條
We will slice the cabbage into strips first.
# 切完了一腌，回家一吃
And we will marinate them.
# 這個別給切斷了，我們浮浮的
Don't cut the cabbage all the way through though.
# 個到這兒，這麽長，對
See, it's about this long.
# 今天這個菜出不了，得燉一天
We won't be able to eat this dish today. It has to be marinated overnight.
# 我們擱盆裏邊腌上
We will put the cabbage in the bowl and marinate overnight.
# 等明天裝盤的時候，拿筷子挑出來
And tomorrow we can just use chopsticks to take them out.
# 咔一到，一刀兩段
By the time we will cut them in half completely.
# 這個吃起來就好吃了
And it will taste good.
# 這個菜叫一刀兩段
This dish is, therefore, also called: Chop them in half.
# 我現在先給他撒點鹽，咱們一層一層撒
We will add some salt first, layer by layer.
# 我們現在給它腌上，腌十五分鐘
Now, we need to marinate them for 15 minutes.
# 然後現在我先炒一個汁
I will make the sauce at the same time.
# 來點兒油
Add some vegetable oil.
# 你看看二伯，精誠合作啊
Er Bai is cooperating so well with you!
# 還得來，這個油吃白菜，油得大一點
Add more, the napa cabbage will absorb lots of oil
# 別等到油太熱了，下鍋
We can put them in now. We don't have to heat up the oil all the way.
# 買不着辣椒絲，把乾辣椒泡軟了
If you can't buy chili strips, you can soak the dried chilis in water,
# 拿剪子較成絲
and cut them into strips with a scissor when they turn soft.
# 喔 酸香酸香
Wow, sour and aromatic.
# 你看大爺，很有經驗
Da Ye has lots of cooking experience.
# 大爺你看見沒有，辣椒他較
He uses scissor to cut chilis.
# 要是切可費了勁了
It would be much harder to use a knife.
# 個點葱薑絲
Add some spring onion and ginger strips.
# 來點礦泉水
Some spring water.
# 忘情水
No love water (same syllable as "spring water").
# 加點糖一塊熬
Add some sugar.
# 大爺補點 再來點水
Da Ye, we need more water.
# 這可不加什麽調料了
We won't add any extra seasoning,
# 就是糖
just sugar.
# 要想甜，必擱鹽
If you want sweetness, you have to add salt.
# 鹽沒少擱啊
That's a lot of salt.
# 鹽我擱的少
Actaully, not a lot,
# 因爲我們殺這白菜還有味呢
since we have already put salt into our napa cabbage.
# 鹽擱了6克啊
We have just add 6 grams of salt.
# 這時候加糖
Now, let's add sugar.
# 我們家糖全讓你們倆用光了
You guys have used all of the sugar in my house.
# 誰説得你也沒少用啊
Sounds as if you didn't use any of them.
# 這熬到什麽程度呢 要冒泡
We have to wait until it starts bubbling,
# 要起黏兒 有點起拉黏
and a little sticky.
# 然後我們最後在個點白醋
Lastly, we will add some white vinegar.
# 這個珊瑚白菜現在基本上上有好多酒店都不買了
Lots of restaurants don't even make Coral Napa Cabbage nowadays.
# 過去是咱們那年代賣的 現在這年代不賣了
They made this dish back in our time, but not anymore.
# 冒泡了吧
It's bubbling.
# 這叫珊瑚白菜
This is Coral Nappa Cabbage.
# 好啦 這回差不多了
Okay, we are almost done.
# 嘿漂亮啊
So beautiful.
# 像不像珊瑚 像
Doesn't it look like coral? Yes.
# 往底下放點涼水 給它鎮上
We will use cold water to cool it down.
# 三叔家是要啥有啥啊
San Shu has everything in his house.
# 它涼了給他個點醋 白醋
We can also drizzle some white vinegar.
# 這樣呢它涼的就快了
To make it cool down faster.
# 待會呢找一塊乾毛巾
Then, we will get a towel.
# 攥白菜 對
To absorb the excess water of the cabbage.
# 他還得要求這整齊 別把白菜的形狀給破壞了
But we can't break the shape of the cabbage.
# 白菜啊
Napa Cabbage.
# 小珊瑚汁多漂亮啊
Coral sauce is just adorable.
# 這叫珊瑚白菜
This is what we call Coral Napa Cabbage.
# 好 真漂亮
Okay, so beautiful.
# 珊瑚白菜 又是一個菜
Coral Napa Cabbage.
# import ending.srt 00:03:47,000